Super sexbots... built to kill!
Dr. Goldfoot and the Bikini Machine is a comedy, science
fiction film directed by Norman Taurog.
In this campy spy movie spoof Dr.
Goldfoot (Vincent Price) has invented an army of bikini-clad robots who are programmed
to seek out wealthy men and charm them into signing over their assets.
Secret agent Craig Gamble (Frankie Avalon) and millionaire Todd
Armstrong set out to foil his fiendish plot.
Dr. Goldfoot, played by Vincent Price.
Craig Gamble, played by Frankie Avalon.
Todd Armstrong, played by Dwayne Hickman.
Diane, played by Susan Hart.
Igor, played by Jack Mullaney.
D.J. Pevney, played by Fred Clark.
Goldfoot and the Bikini Machine is a 1965 American Pathécolor comedy film directed
by Norman Taurog and distributed by American International Pictures.
Starring Vincent Price, Frankie Avalon, Dwayne Hickman, Susan Hart and Jack Mullaney, and featuring Fred Clark, the film
is a parody of the then-popular spy trend (the title is a spoof of two James Bond films: the 1962 film Dr.
No and the 1964 hit Goldfinger), made using actors from
AIP's beach party and Edgar Allan Poe films.
The film was retitled Dr G.
and the Bikini Machine in England due to a threatened lawsuit from
Eon, holder of the rights to the James Bond series.
Hickman called it "AIP's attempt to combine horror, bikini babe and secret agents
and take advantage of the popularity of the James Bond pictures".
Despite its low production values, the film has achieved a certain cult status for the appearance of horror legend Price and AIP's beach party film alumni,
its in-jokes and over-the-top sexuality, the claymation title sequence designed by Art Clokey, and a title song performed by The Supremes.
Its success led to a sequel, produced in 1966, entitled Dr.
Goldfoot and the Girl Bombs.
The film explores themes of secret agent, mad
scientist, bikini, robot, world domination.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.